Captioning provided by
MUHSEN (www.muhsen.org)
- In this episode,
we want to move on to how the simplicity
of the prophet's lifestyle,
peace and blessings be upon him,
and the humility with
which he carried himself
is yet another strong endorsement
for his claim to prophethood.
(atmospheric chiming)
You see the lifestyle of the prophets,
Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam,
was a true testament that his mission
could not have been self-serving.
And, we can read all throughout history
about imposter prophets.
What were their lives like?
What were their personalities like?
Their pretentious behavior,
their decadent lifestyles,
their extravagance,
and their exploitation of others.
Whereas, the Prophet Muhammad,
peace and blessings be upon him,
at the end of his mission,
he became the undisputed ruler of Arabia.
Yet, you find no semblance of luxury
in any sphere of his life.
His living quarters were tight and meager,
to the point that his wife
says he would tap her leg
when he would want to
prostrate in his night vigils,
in his night prayers,
so he would have room to place
his forehead on the ground.
The Prophet Muhammad, peace
and blessings be upon him,
one month after another,
after another, she says,
would pass
without any fire being
kindled in his house,
meaning no cooking, meaning no meats.
And, there would be nothing
but water and dates, she said,
unless one of his companions
would gift him a jug of milk.
One time, Umar ibn al-Khaṭṭāb,
may Allah be pleased with him,
walked in and saw that little water skin
hanging in the prophets room,
and the straw mats that he slept on,
having left marks on his side.
So, out of sympathy for
the great prophet of God,
he had an emotional meltdown, he cried.
And, the Prophet Muhammad,
peace and blessings be upon him,
asked him, "What makes you cry?"
He said, "How can this be?
You are God's prophet, God's
final messenger to humanity.
And, you will live like
this, a life of hardships.
While Rome and Persia have emperors
that are frolicking in
their gardens and meadows,
enjoying their fountains and springs,
how can this be?"
And, so the Prophet Muhammad,
peace and blessings be upon him,
said to him, "Are you in doubt, Umar?
Are you in doubt regarding
the reward of the Hereafter?
These are a people whose pleasures
whose enjoyment has been
expedited for them in this,
meaning this, this shallow world.
Don't you know,
don't you remember,
that for them is this world,
and for us, is the Hereafter?"
You know the famous historian,
Washington Irving,
upon citing how Mohammed,
peace and blessings be upon him,
in all the biographical reports about him,
would milk his own animal,
and he would sew, stitch his own clothing,
and was a human,
just like any other human being,
except that he claimed to
receive revelation from God.
Washington Irving says,
this was a man who never indulged
in the magnificence of apparel,
he says, which is the
ostentation of a petty mind.
Meaning, only foolish
people show off in this way.
Whereas, Mohammed was
above seeking validation
from such a trivial source,
meaning materialism.
When he would arrive at a gathering,
he would not like it
that anyone rise for him
and his companion, Anas ibn
Mâlik, radi'Allahu anhu,
would say, "We used to want
to stand up in salutation
out of honor for him,
to honor him with our
greeting as we stand erect,
but we knew how much he hated that,
and that was the only
thing that kept us seated."
He was the greatest educator of all time
that still was never ashamed to say,
"I don't know."
He was the busiest statesmen of all time,
yet he would allow the
weakest members of society
to take him by hand to
wherever they needed.
He was the greatest husband of all time,
that still left room
and was sensitive enough to notice
when his wives happened
to be upset at him.
He was the greatest prophet
and messenger of all time.
And, yet he would still say to the people,
do not aggrandized me.
Don't overpraise me
the way they did with my brother,
Jesus, the son of Mary,
I am but a slave.
So, say the slave of God,
the servant of God and His messenger,
and in another beautiful hadith,
he said, "The example of me,
and the previous prophets before me,
is like the example of
a magnificent building,
a brilliant building that
people walk around it and say,
'How marvelous.'
Were it not for this one missing brick
in one of its corners.
He says, I am just that brick.
I am that brick.
And, I am the seal of the prophets."
Captioning provided by
MUHSEN (www.muhsen.org)