Captioning provided by
MUHSEN (www.muhsen.org)
Some people seem to have
it so hard in this life,
and others seem to be living it up.
But don't stare too long at
the lofty palaces and homes
or the wild parties and seemingly
unrestricted self-worship,
where people are led by their every desire
or through your phone
at the highly filtered
happiness of others.
Because behind those screens
and beneath those layers
may be pain and emptiness
of a different type.
And whatever our states
may seem like in this life,
our inevitable fate is the same,
but things are not always what they seem.
Within those graves are gardens of reward
or chambers of punishment.
And within our hearts is either
the pleasure of certainty
in knowing that there
is something far greater
than this world or the pain of emptiness
and not knowing at all.
Oh believer, this world was
not meant to be your paradise,
but knowing that paradise awaits
makes this journey so much
more bearable and rewardable.
Because while every
difficulty is temporary,
every moment is an opportunity.
And you know that if you get this right,
that after all your struggles,
after all your tests and trials,
after all your loves and losses,
your eternal sanctuary awaits.
Built by your deeds and
decorated by your duas,
a jewel encrusted crown
for a verse once recited,
chalets of crystal
sparkling on the horizon
for a soul that gave up sin,
tree trunks of green emerald
and branches of gold for a
simple word of remembrance.
The company of blessed people you chose
to accompany, who strove like you
and from past generations
you chose to follow
that taught you how to strive.
Each of your shuddering breaths,
every second of discomfort you faced
and every one of your sacrifices,
all have been accounted for,
repaid with sights and rewards
unimaginable and the
company of the most high.
Build your eternal home.
Decorate your eternal home.
Long for your eternal home.
Welcome to your eternal home.
Captioning provided by
MUHSEN (www.muhsen.org)